[{"id": "58b8cee294b094db915830ab", "question": "Who is credited with creating McDonald\u2019s\u2019 Big Mac?", "answer": "Jim Delligatti", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398d2", "question": "The Flintstones lived in what city?", "answer": "Bedrock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be86", "question": "What type of a tree killed Sonny Bono?", "answer": "Pine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd0", "question": "In what city was the Wright brothers' bicycle shop?", "answer": "Dayton, Ohio", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe775edeec85e375820b313", "question": "How many states does Mexico have?", "answer": "31", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399aa", "question": "What 1990 John Hughes move was hyped as \"a family comedy, without the family\"?", "answer": "Home Alone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ec4d08d98002fdd633ba", "question": "Which character, that first appeared in the book \"Winnie-the-Pooh\", loves watercress?", "answer": "Roo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad9", "question": "What Grand Slam sports event is held at Flushing Meadows, NY?", "answer": "US Open", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af76", "question": "What were American patriots protesting when they dumped tea into Boston Harbor?", "answer": "Taxation without representation", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4d9a4e08b8581f80b092bb", "question": "Which month saw the release of the film \"Star Wars: The Last Jedi\"?", "answer": "December", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339037", "question": "What is non-rhyming poetry called?", "answer": "Blank verse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fed2be1ec223966ae8f8914", "question": "Who wrote The Monkees' #1 hit \"I'm a Believer\"?", "answer": "Neil Diamond", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9b3", "question": "Where are the Sigatoka sand dunes located?", "answer": "Fiji", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf4", "question": "How many Grammy Awards did Frank Sinatra receive during his career?", "answer": "11", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b099", "question": "In what year was the Richter scale developed?", "answer": "1935", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600b882c1d8c1817608d53ee", "question": "What Italian term is used to describe pasta or rice that has been cooked until it is slightly firm to bite?", "answer": "Al dente", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8bf", "question": "What plant is traditionally worn on St. Patrick's Day?", "answer": "Shamrock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd662ec223966ae8f88d2", "question": "On the TV show \"How I Met Your Mother\", what is Lily\u2019s occupation?", "answer": "Kindergarten Teacher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa4ab6ce05a3942286eb7", "question": "What is the name of the cat in the film \"Alien\"?", "answer": "Jonsey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd92", "question": "Many Bothan spies died to ensure the destruction of what?", "answer": "The Second Death Star", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a2e", "question": "What university did David Letterman graduate from in 1969 with a degree in telecommunications?", "answer": "Ball State", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af0b", "question": "During what century was the Mexican War fought?", "answer": "19th Century", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f52", "question": "What song begins with the words \"Betty, is that Jimmy's ring you're wearing?\"?", "answer": "Leader of the Pack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5901d9e6709c1c34536e6ead", "question": "The fans of Taylor Swift are known as what?", "answer": "Swifties", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdffb161cf6db9ac4808cf4", "question": "Where is the largest natural amphitheater in the U.S.?", "answer": "Los Angeles, California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c018", "question": "What is the Italian name for squid in a restaurant?\u00a0", "answer": "Calamari\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c8a67b90aac110e416707e", "question": "In \"Alice in Wonderland\", who did Alice see taking tea under a tree?", "answer": "Mad Hatter and March Hare", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef61f16ce05a3942286e59", "question": "What does the \"MS\" reference in \"MSNBC\"?", "answer": "Microsoft", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f4a0ff048f679a45aac7", "question": "What is the largest object in the asteroid belt that lies between the orbits of Mars and Jupiter?", "answer": "Ceres", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b345", "question": "In what year did Captain Cook reach New Zealand?", "answer": "1769", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a89e", "question": "What islands are home to most of the world's blue-footed boobies?", "answer": "The Galapagos Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefa3df6ce05a3942286eac", "question": "Which Oscar-winner studied opera as a teen?", "answer": "Meryl Streep", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0fe", "question": "Which cartoon character has an arch enemy called \"Hugo A-Go-Go\"?", "answer": "Batfink", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c065", "question": "In the video game \"Darksiders\", which of the Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse do you play?", "answer": "War", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b0d", "question": "What does the comic book character Galactus eat?", "answer": "Planets", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fcf", "question": "What TV show did \"A Different World\" spin off from?", "answer": "The Cosby Show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8b4eec223966ae8f883a", "question": "The movie \"Rush Hour 2\" poked humor at China for consuming which type of animal meat?", "answer": "Dog", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a5", "question": "Which Flintstones character was absent from the Flintstone vitamins until 1996?", "answer": "Betty Rubble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339487", "question": "Who played the role of Archie Leach in the 1988 movie \"A Fish Called Wanda\"?", "answer": "John Cleese", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a446", "question": "What mountain overlooks Cape Town, South Africa?", "answer": "Table Mountain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abf5", "question": "Adelaide is the capital of which Australian state?", "answer": "South Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe37b0e0ada16518afdc05f", "question": "In what year did Soviet Russia finally declare war on Japan?", "answer": "1945", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6a7596c0f9723ab15cb5e", "question": "Which US college or university has the largest endowment?", "answer": "Harvard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e851fe83fe1f2a824bda", "question": "What were the four humours that the ancient Greeks believed made up the body and determined illness?", "answer": "Blood, phlegm, black bile, yellow bile", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d1", "question": "What is the capital of New Mexico?", "answer": "Santa Fe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bb5", "question": "What actor played James Bond in two Bond films in between Roger Moore's Bond and Pierce Brosnan's?", "answer": "Timothy Dalton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6007813cbd51d85e222ab649", "question": "What quality is associated with peaches in Chinese art?", "answer": "Peaches symbolizing immortality (or the wish for a long and healthy life) are a common symbol in Chinese art.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bdc", "question": "Lenny Kravtiz is the son of what popular sitcom actress?", "answer": "Roxie Roker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bcb", "question": "In what English city was Boy George born?", "answer": "London", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd96c8623c87fd04dd15e26", "question": "Which U.S. president received offers to play in the NFL?", "answer": "Gerald Ford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe904cd01dd7bf43be5e878", "question": "The Miami Marlins' baseball stadium is built on the former site of what other stadium?", "answer": "The Orange Bowl Stadium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8aaba01dd7bf43be5e75f", "question": "Chartreuse is a color between yellow and what?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5cd86ce05a3942286e27", "question": "What kick does Daniel use to win the tournament in \"The Karate Kid\"?", "answer": "Crane kick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f45", "question": "What sheriff's alter ego was the masked \"El Kabong\"?", "answer": "Quick Draw McGraw's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133991f", "question": "What was the name of the first spin-off from the TV show \"Law & Order\"?", "answer": "Law & Order: SVU", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6000ecd09a72b906b34e3ce6", "question": "The adjective \"cutaneous\" relates to which part of the human body?", "answer": "Skin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ad7e7e0b24f84e0b9f9ffc0", "question": "Which state surrounds the Australian Capital Territory?", "answer": "New South Wales", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac6", "question": "What month and year was National Geographic magazine first published?", "answer": "October 1888", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7f7", "question": "The electric eel is native only to what continent?", "answer": "South America", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339085", "question": "What is considered as the first daily comic strip in the US?", "answer": "Mutt and Jeff", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc4", "question": "By including cannon fire in his play, Henry VIII, Shakespeare caused the 1613 fire that destroyed what building?", "answer": "The Globe Theatre", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f8", "question": "The infamous glitch Pokemon \"missingno\" is found in the games Pokemon Red and what else?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c29c", "question": "What is the astronomical term for the distance light travels in a vacuum in one year?", "answer": "Light-year", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffcfc259dc5ec6cd98a831a", "question": "Which painting depicts melting watches?", "answer": "Salvador Dal\u00ed's \"The Persistence of Memory\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c291", "question": "How many equal sides are there on a scalene triangle?", "answer": "None", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5d0", "question": "What was the last desktop computer made by Commodore?", "answer": "The Amiga 4000", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb8e67e83c707845b2136", "question": "What is the longest snake in the world?", "answer": "Reticulated python", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff14722b0ee8c595b6d39c3", "question": "What was Sleeping Beauty poisoned by?", "answer": "A spindle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c5", "question": "What year marked the publishing of Bram Stoker's novel \"Dracula\"?", "answer": "1897", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338932", "question": "What is the given name of the famous German composer and pianist Beethoven?", "answer": "Ludwig", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339592", "question": "Who played the wives in the movie \"The First Wives Club\"?", "answer": "Bette Midler, Goldie Hawn and Diane Keaton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c3508815febcc896f9258", "question": "In which country would you find the motor racing circuit called Kyalami?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391fb", "question": "Who played Vincent Vega in \"Pulp Fiction\"?", "answer": "John Travolta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133996f", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Apu's last name?", "answer": "Nahasapeemapetilon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590678e5ff9c0647b50a804d", "question": "What month, in 2016, did the World Trade Organization announce an outbreak of the Zika virus?", "answer": "January", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4be", "question": "When did the Seychelles gain their independence from the United Kingdom?", "answer": "June 29, 1975", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f735ca9e54d890926f6f0", "question": "What word comes from the name of a hot spring in Iceland?", "answer": "Geyser -- The term refers to a specific geyser named Geysir, which means \"the gusher\" from the Old Norse \"geysa\" for \"to gush\".", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac5", "question": "What year was National Geographic magazine first published?", "answer": "1888", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d87", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Calvin Broadus?", "answer": "Snoop Dogg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937e9a508d98002fdd6339b", "question": "Who is Donald Duck's girlfriend?", "answer": "Daisy Duck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59008b7acf842fa4c4ba9699", "question": "What is a funambulist?", "answer": "Tightrope walker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a904", "question": "What major river runs through Washington D.C.?", "answer": "Potomac", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b71b", "question": "What do South Africans decorate at Christmas time with cotton, wool and tinsel?", "answer": "Their windows", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b36a", "question": "What was invented by Dr Albert P. Southwick in the 1880's?", "answer": "Electric chair", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b06f", "question": "What famous ship was sunk on May 7, 1915?", "answer": "The Lusitania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b13a", "question": "What is the name of President's George Washington's 500 acre Virginia estate, and current tourist attraction?", "answer": "Mount Vernon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b30301dd7bf43be5e7a6", "question": "What flower symbolizes indifference according to the Old Farmer\u2019s Almanac?", "answer": "Candytuft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b5", "question": "Which French fashion designer created the conical bra for Madonna's \"Blond Ambition\" tour?", "answer": "Jean-Paul Gaultier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391be", "question": "In which film did Paul Newman play a crime boss named John Rooney?", "answer": "Road to Perdition", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4d979d08b8581f80b092aa", "question": "What name was given to the tropical cyclone that destroyed large parts of the Houston metropolitan area in the United States in August of 2017?", "answer": "Hurricane Harvey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a969", "question": "What California peak, which erupted in 1915, is the world's largest lava dome?", "answer": "Lassen Peak", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e6bc89fb6c85e9e634ff5d", "question": "Majorca belongs to which island group?", "answer": "Balearic Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4f7", "question": "What is the street address of the White House?", "answer": "1600 Pennsylvania Avenue", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60078250bd51d85e222ab656", "question": "What did Claude Monet's father want him to be?", "answer": "Grocer (Monet's father disapproved of his painting. He wanted him to go into the family\u00a0grocery business.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c3e9816ebfabb9c85d8a969", "question": "In Formula One what does it mean when a black flag is being waved?", "answer": "Disqualification", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008b61cf842fa4c4ba9698", "question": "How was American comedian and actor, William Claude Dukenfield, better known as?", "answer": "WC Fields\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad85", "question": "What decade saw the first US postage stamp issued?", "answer": "1840s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff66e6952a821ff76ae8b1b", "question": "What did people often say for photos before \"cheese\"?", "answer": "When Richard Beard, Britain's first portrait photographer, began taking family portraits, he told his clients to say \"prunes\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c84a", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find hepatocytes?", "answer": "The liver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa17", "question": "What country borders Egypt to the south?", "answer": "Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab9e", "question": "What was Saint Petersburg called immediately before being renamed to Leningrad?", "answer": "Petrograd", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad9", "question": "Who created the \"Spy vs Spy\" silent comic strip?", "answer": "Antonio Prohias", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394fc", "question": "In the TV series \"Doctor Who\", what does the acronym TARDIS stand for?", "answer": "Time and Relative Dimension in Space", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff3c0704f032c0db195b476", "question": "Before he escaped and returned to France, Napoleon had been exiled to what island in 1814?", "answer": "Elba", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a70d", "question": "Which US state is home to the Hopi Indian Reservation?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c7", "question": "What is the name of Warren Beaty's famous sister?", "answer": "Shirley MacLaine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ff", "question": "What US vice president referred to his critics as \"nattering nabobs of negativism\"?", "answer": "Spiro Agnew", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d117a64fea7fe947a2227b", "question": "Which Englishman was famously beheaded on October 29th, 1618?", "answer": "Walter Raleigh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8e2", "question": "Which Washington, D.C. street is often used as shorthand for the lobbying industry?", "answer": "K", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d42", "question": "What artist painted the popular \"The Night Watch\" painting?", "answer": "Rembrandt", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c12", "question": "What year saw the debut of the TV show \"South Park\"?", "answer": "1997", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c5", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is Smithers' first name?", "answer": "Waylon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c59", "question": "Who was the faithful wife of Ulysses in Homer\u2019s \"Odyssey\"?", "answer": "Penelope", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb36", "question": "What is the three letter name of the red, brimless hat which originated in Morocco?", "answer": "Fez", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b59501dd7bf43be5e7d2", "question": "What was Big Ben renamed to in 2012?", "answer": "Elizabeth Tower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b885e662d71a53651025", "question": "Which German painter was sometimes court painter to King Henry VIII of England after 1536?", "answer": "Hans Holbein the Younger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b349", "question": "Who was the first woman to sail single-handed around the world?", "answer": "Naomi James", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdabb020b8cce1e6fda7059", "question": "Who invented \"Jell-O\"?", "answer": "Pearl Wait", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d2", "question": "\"The Running of the Bulls\" event is held in what Spanish city?", "answer": "Pamplona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd82431d0de9af39e9d46b8", "question": "What was Memorial Day originally known as?", "answer": "Decoration Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ff", "question": "What was The Police's biggest selling single?", "answer": "Every Breath You Take", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921f", "question": "What is the collective name for Italian-made western movies?", "answer": "Spaghetti westerns", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b490049076251badbeaaa", "question": "The Treaty of Ghent was the peace treaty that ended which war?", "answer": "War of 1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e2", "question": "What fruit comes in Redhaven and Harmony variety?", "answer": "Peaches", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca2", "question": "First published in 1988, who wrote the book \"A Brief History of Time\"?", "answer": "Stephen Hawking", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a39", "question": "What poet penned \"Ash Wednesday\" in 1930?", "answer": "T.S. Eliot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9a3", "question": "What river was connected to Lake Erie by the Erie Canal?", "answer": "The Hudson River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4a96f561d1b4d384d5d67e", "question": "What character first appeared in the film \"The Wise Little Hen\"?", "answer": "Donald Duck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2e4", "question": "Where did two lanterns historically hang on the night of April 18, 1775?", "answer": "Boston's Old North Church", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c04b", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of the Bahamas?", "answer": "American flamingo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fde4e82c6c6b019850c9a84", "question": "November 11, 1921 marked the first anonymous burial at what famous U.S. cemetery?", "answer": "Arlington National Cemetery", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5b5", "question": "What relative of the raccoon is sometimes known as the cat-bear?", "answer": "The Panda", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a0d", "question": "What was the title of the Kirstie Alley TV show in which her character ran a lingerie company?", "answer": "Veronica's Closet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c172", "question": "What does a dowser do?", "answer": "Find water", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feddcad6ce05a3942286d9e", "question": "Who hosts the Potterwatch pirate radio show?", "answer": "Lee Jordan hosts Potterwatch to advise listeners on defenses against Lord Voldemort.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc19eec223966ae8f886b", "question": "What princess was traditionally called Badr al-Budur (or Badroulbadour) before Disney renamed her?", "answer": "Jasmine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdab4fa0b8cce1e6fda7049", "question": "What English word has the most definitions/meanings?", "answer": "Run", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97e", "question": "What would you add to a Welsh Rarebit to make a Buck Rarebit?", "answer": "Poached Egg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef96796ce05a3942286e9d", "question": "Which U.S. sitcom was the first to use a laugh track?", "answer": "\"The Hank McCune Show\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a826", "question": "What is the capital of Kenya?", "answer": "Nairobi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e5", "question": "In \"Rocky 3\" what does Apollo Creed give as a gift before he fights \"Clubber\" Lang?", "answer": "Boxing trunks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c67b", "question": "What is the main source of food for the badger?", "answer": "Earthworms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1a3", "question": "What product was originally called \"Baby Gays\"?", "answer": "Q-Tips", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133947a", "question": "In the movie \"Lilo and Stitch\", what city does Stitch build and then destroy in the bedroom?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b3ce01dd7bf43be5e7b5", "question": "What TV show inspired the term \"spam\" for junk email?", "answer": "\"Monty Python's Flying Circus\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601217d863c99d48cd169aeb", "question": "What dog breed has a name that translates to \"little brushwood dog\"?", "answer": "Shiba Inu", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff20e6e31a458464a93c422", "question": "In which Franz Kafka novel did the main character turn into a cockroach?", "answer": "Metamorphosis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f3", "question": "What sport was once contested with a spadroon?", "answer": "Fencing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a363", "question": "What is the capital of Bulgaria?", "answer": "Sofia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d2c", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Fat City\"?", "answer": "Boxing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b536", "question": "What does an archer carry his arrows in?", "answer": "A Quiver", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ee", "question": "Killer Whales are more commonly seen on which North American coast?", "answer": "West coast", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba38", "question": "What nickname was given to the Indianapolis Motor Speedway in 1909?", "answer": "Brickyard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338faf", "question": "Who is Snoopy's arch enemy?", "answer": "The Red Baron", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec8922ec223966ae8f8826", "question": "Who is the artist who sings \"Beauty School Dropout\" in the movie \"Grease\"?", "answer": "Frankie Avalon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec9", "question": "What kind of blood is dumped on Stephen King's \"Carrie\"?", "answer": "Pig's blood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fde499cc6c6b019850c9a70", "question": "The infamous War of the Roses was mainly between which two English counties?", "answer": "Lancashire And Yorkshire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a25f1596682715b82711cdf", "question": "What year was the ice cream cone patented in UK?", "answer": "1902", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a538", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Tar Heel State\"?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cae8", "question": "What is the study of soils in their natural environment called?", "answer": "Pedology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde4", "question": "Where is the Basketball Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Springfield, Massachusetts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c55d", "question": "What are the four main ingredients of concrete?", "answer": "Sand, water, cement, gravel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febb08b7e83c707845b2105", "question": "What\u2019s the botanical term for the stem of a fruit or vegetable?", "answer": "Peduncle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396f2", "question": "What is tattooed on Popeye\u2019s arm?", "answer": "An anchor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339276", "question": "What movie stars Adam Sandler and Drew Barrymore and takes place in Hawaii?", "answer": "50 First Dates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee1", "question": "What bird was used as an alias for Tom Clancy's CIA agent in the Kremlin?", "answer": "The Cardinal", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e93", "question": "Who made his West End debut playing alongside his mother in \"South Pacific\"?", "answer": "Larry Hagman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5be57c9c5415ba52ed6f0aa3", "question": "What is Sterling Archer's codename on the cartoon series \"Archer\"?", "answer": "Duchess", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133933a", "question": "Who is Charlie's nephew on the TV show \"Two and a Half Men\"?", "answer": "Jake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad27", "question": "What Undersecretary of the United Nations became the first African-American to win the Nobel Peace Prize?", "answer": "Ralph Bunche", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef93fe6ce05a3942286e93", "question": "What show did \"TV Guide\" name the \"best TV show of all time\" in 2002?", "answer": "\"Seinfeld\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce3", "question": "What film's title character is the only one who can see a giant demonic rabbit name Frank?", "answer": "Donnie Darko", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69f1720565ad31a57c78a", "question": "The first woman to run for president chose whom as her running mate?", "answer": "Fredrick Douglas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd66d94a5bfecdd737e08a3", "question": "What was the most popular month for weddings in the U.S. in 2019?", "answer": "October", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af00", "question": "Who was the 16th president of the US?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909d291bb53d1af6588650b", "question": "What toy was Arnold Schwarzenegger after in the movie \"Jingle All the Way\"?", "answer": "Turbo-Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b267", "question": "What empress gave John Paul Jones a navy job after his American military career ended?", "answer": "Catherine the Great", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dde", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"mammoth\"?", "answer": "Russian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb9d", "question": "What national news magazine published its first issue in February 1933, as a competitor of \"Time\"?", "answer": "Newsweek", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd6efec223966ae8f88d7", "question": "In \"Goodfellas\" Billy Batts dooms himself by asking Tommy to get a what?", "answer": "A shinebox", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c37", "question": "George Catlin is best known for his paintings of whom?", "answer": "American Indians", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f23", "question": "What was comedian Redd Foxx's real last name?", "answer": "Sanford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd48", "question": "In soccer, how many yellow cards lead to a player's disqualification?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd66dc0a5bfecdd737e08a6", "question": "How many candles are lit throughout the eight nights of Hanukkah?", "answer": "44", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397c9", "question": "In the 1994 movie \"Jumanji\", a stampede is released, what is the last animal to appear?", "answer": "Rhinoceros", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eaf", "question": "Whose children's books involve a mysterious organization known only as \"V.F.D.\"?", "answer": "Lemony Snicket's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf9", "question": "In which movie did Tilda Swinton portray a witch?", "answer": "The Lion, the Witch and the Wardrobe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d45", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Anna and the King\"?", "answer": "Bai Ling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c8f9fbde8045e48466e5", "question": "After dogs, what is thought to be the first domesticated farm animal?", "answer": "Goats were the first farm animal to be domesticated according to many historians.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b9", "question": "According to the old rhyme, Monday's child is fair of face. What is Tuesday's child full of?", "answer": "Grace", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396bc", "question": "U2's David Evans is better known by which nickname?", "answer": "The Edge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c11e", "question": "Harvey Lee Yeary became famous under what name?", "answer": "Lee Majors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae0d", "question": "Who was the first female commander of NASA's Space Shuttle?", "answer": "Eileen Collins", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe657daae7e414034b5aee3", "question": "In the Book of Deuteronomy, which mountain is also known as the Mount of Blessing?", "answer": "Mount Gerizim", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f0", "question": "What company makes the Xbox console?", "answer": "Microsoft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339677", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Springfield's music store?", "answer": "King Toot's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c9f", "question": "In \"The Wizard of Oz\", what was Dorothy's uncle's name?", "answer": "Henry", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b076", "question": "What Israeli prime minister was assassinated in 1995?", "answer": "Yitzhak Rabin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a2", "question": "Who authored 1883's \"The Adventures of Pinocchio\"?", "answer": "Carlo Collodi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f87", "question": "What is Dame Margott Fonteyn famous\u00a0for?", "answer": "Ballet dancing", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fed2bd0ec223966ae8f8913", "question": "In the film \"Dances with Wolves,\" what happens to Dunbar's diary?", "answer": "It's used as toilet paper.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b371", "question": "In World War II, where was the defensive line known as the \"Gin Drinkers Line\"?", "answer": "Hong Kong", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8b0", "question": "Miranda orbits what planet of the solar system?", "answer": "Uranus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa3ccfc73aa70ea0b70aef", "question": "Which country shares part of its name with its capital?", "answer": "The capital of El Salvador is San Salvador. The city lies below the slopes of the San Salvador volcano, for which it is named.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef65306ce05a3942286e69", "question": "Where is the famous Coachella music festival held?", "answer": "Imdio, California", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c1f", "question": "Which body part was Achilles weak spot?", "answer": "His heel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef669f6ce05a3942286e7a", "question": "How many of the original three Star Wars films did George Lucas direct?", "answer": "One", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe25a30658e585fda9cfa44", "question": "What does the term \"au gratin\" mean when it comes to cooking?", "answer": "Covered with browned crust, often breadcrumbs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c9250775fa611bce67e8", "question": "What is hummus made from?", "answer": "Chickpeas -- Hummus is Arabic for \"chickpeas.\" It is a Middle Eastern dish common throughout the Mediterranean region and beyond.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd81f38d0de9af39e9d4694", "question": "What was the highest value of U.S. currency ever put into circulation?", "answer": "$10,000 bill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b03de662d71a53650fc4", "question": "What feature marks the entrance to the Louvre?", "answer": "Glass pyramid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a162d06f01ec323f8491735", "question": "What do O.J Simpson's initials stand for?", "answer": "Orenthal James", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b70a", "question": "According to Irish superstition, what stands open during the 12 days of Christmas?", "answer": "The gates of heaven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c750", "question": "The Latin prefix \"pulmo\u00ad\" refers to what organ of the human body?", "answer": "Lung", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c429", "question": "Which astronomer gave his name to a telescope launched into space in 1990?", "answer": "Edwin Hubble", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea3312ff048f679a45aaeb", "question": "What is the loudest animal on Earth?", "answer": "Sperm whale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca3", "question": "Oliver Mellors was the proper name of what D.H. Lawrence title character?", "answer": "Lady Chatterley's Lover", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133901d", "question": "Sidney Paget is famous for creating the visual image of which literary character?", "answer": "Sherlock Holmes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf3", "question": "What US state's National Guard still calls itself \"the Green Mountain Boys\"?", "answer": "Vermont", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399fc", "question": "What 1992 film features the characters Colonel Nathan Jessup and Lieutenant Daniel Kaffee?", "answer": "A Few Good Men", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a05c", "question": "What 2005 movie's tagline is \"The longer you wait, the harder it gets\"?", "answer": "The 40 Year Old Virgin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb3c", "question": "What NHL team won the 2011 Stanley Cup in hockey?", "answer": "Boston Bruins", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb5b525dad637d903c8819", "question": "In what city will you find Le Bourget Airport?", "answer": "Paris, France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c578", "question": "What nearby galaxy is name for a mythological princess?", "answer": "Andromeda Galaxy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a94", "question": "What was the title of the 2007 Larry the Cable Guy movie where he played a bumbling Army reservist?", "answer": "Delta Farce", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc1b", "question": "What team bought Babe Ruth from the Boston Red Sox?", "answer": "The New York Yankees", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015def4fe83fe1f2a824b75", "question": "What percent of Russian males born in 1923 survived World War II?", "answer": "20%", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ac", "question": "What is Homer Simpson's middle initial?", "answer": "J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c59d", "question": "What word denotes the energy an object has because it is in motion?", "answer": "Kinetic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "590499eacf93664eb1048695", "question": "Which 1950s film took place in Chicago and Miami in 1929?", "answer": "Some Like it Hot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b524", "question": "What is Prosciutto?", "answer": "Italian dry-cured ham", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae88", "question": "What general became a national hero for his defense of New Orleans during the War of 1812?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60078c700eee65b76b9f2673", "question": "What is the Statue of Liberty holding in her left hand?", "answer": "She holds a tablet inscribed with the date of the U.S. Declaration of Independence \u2014 July 4, 1776. It is nearly 24 ft. long.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba4d", "question": "By what name was basketball coach Arnold Auerbach better known?", "answer": "Red Auerbach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596371ad967692ea851899bb", "question": "What country music singer was born in Muskogee, Oklahoma in 1983?", "answer": "Carrie Underwood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e6f", "question": "Who draft-dodged the Trojan War by dressing as a woman in the court of King Lycomedes?", "answer": "Achillies", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a08", "question": "What snack shares its name with the famous cartoon strip by Charles M. Schulz?", "answer": "Peanuts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff51a8aff04d658268c9306", "question": "Odysseus left home to fight in what war?", "answer": "Trojan War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b296", "question": "Washington's famous crossing of the Delaware was en route to what Revolutionary War battle?", "answer": "The Battle of Trenton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c792", "question": "Cheetahs are native to what two continents?", "answer": "Africa and Asia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a305", "question": "Who played the role of Hank Moody on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "David Duchovny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339227", "question": "What decade did Marty McFly go back to in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "1950's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8d47f2b42d4a3561a9efa", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", who did Katchoo visit when she disappeared in Canada for 2 months?", "answer": "Emma", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e9", "question": "What kind of creature is Mowgli's enemy Shere Khan in \"The Jungle Book\"?", "answer": "Tiger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133894a", "question": "Ray Bradbury's novel \"Fahrenheit 451\" was serialized in the March, April and May issues of what popular magazine?", "answer": "Playboy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdc0c1b469bb8041d07a04d", "question": "\"Open Your Hand And Smile\" has been which product's ad slogan?", "answer": "M&M\"s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe530b71bf59ab7d2e3811a", "question": "What store sells the most wine in the United States?", "answer": "Costco", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5bc", "question": "Which beverage was promoted during the 1990s by three frogs croaking out its name?", "answer": "Budweiser", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeac", "question": "Who was the second president of the United States?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b99d", "question": "Which US state's two letter postal abbreviation is \"HI\"?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a528", "question": "Columbia University is located in which US city?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c54", "question": "Who wrote \"Brave New World\"?", "answer": "Aldous Huxley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a85a", "question": "Which US state is the third largest state by land area?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a79620565ad31a57c7eb", "question": "Which state's flag was designed by a 7th grader?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdff6961cf6db9ac4808cef", "question": "What is the world\u2019s largest plateau?", "answer": "Tibetan Plateau", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60078bd40eee65b76b9f266d", "question": "What was the name of the first English child born in the Americas?", "answer": "Virginia Dare (She was born August 18, 1587 in\u00a0Roanoke Colony.  She and about 120 settlers mysteriously disappeared.)", "category": "history"}]